{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which band includes 'Keith Moon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","India","Taiwan"],"question":"Swahili is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dolomite","incorrectAnswers":["Gypsum","Baking Soda","Marsh Gas"],"question":"What is calcium magnesium carbonate commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Jarrow March","incorrectAnswers":["The Swing Riots","Tolpuddle Martyrs","The Chartists"],"question":"What famous protest took place in Britain in 1936?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tee-ball","incorrectAnswers":["Korf-ball","Kinderball","Knuckleball"],"question":"What is a type of baseball designed for young players who are still developing their hitting skills?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crusaders","incorrectAnswers":["The Zealots","The Infidels","The Righteous"],"question":"Who fought for the Holy Land between 1095 and 1291?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Galata Bridge","incorrectAnswers":["Bosphor Bridge","Istanbul Suspension Bridge","Topkaki Bridge"],"question":"Which Bridge Connects Europe With Asia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["the age of the Earth","puzzles","neural diseases"],"question":"What is Heliology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Corned beef","incorrectAnswers":["Pastrami","Roast beef","Ham"],"question":"What type of meat is found in a Reuben sandwich?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Prince and the Pauper","incorrectAnswers":["The Boy in the Striped Pyjamas","The Name of the Rose","The Hobbit"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'I will set down a tale as it was told to me by one who had it of his father, which latter had it of HIS father, this last having in like manner had it of HIS father—and so on, back and still back, three hundred years and more, the fathers transmitting it to the sons and so preserving it.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Wuthering Heights","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","The Phantom of the Opera","Coraline"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line '1801—I have just returned from a visit to my landlord—the solitary neighbour that I shall be troubled with.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Jane Alexander","Barbara Barrie","Candice Bergen"],"question":"Who won the 1979 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Joanna Kramer in Kramer vs. Kramer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the song 'Erotica'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Sean Connery","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Licence to Kill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bhutan","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Thailand","Bahrain"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Ema Datshi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mary Stuart'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1936","incorrectAnswers":["1926","1916","1906"],"question":"In What Year Did The Spanish Civil War Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Gold","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Norway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"With hard work, all things grow","incorrectAnswers":["The act done by me against my will is not my act","Seize the day","Honey, I'm home"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Grandescunt aucta labore' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chevy Chase","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Martin","Tim Allen","Tom Hanks"],"question":"Who plays the lead role of the accident prone Clark Griswold in the 1989 'National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Martha's Vineyard","incorrectAnswers":["Long Island","Block Island","Cape Cod"],"question":"What is the name of the largest island in Massachusetts, famous for its lush scenery, beaches and celebrity sightings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oxter","incorrectAnswers":["Erf","Futz","Bumfuzzle"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'outdated word meaning “armpit”'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Micronesia","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","China","Malawi"],"question":"Palikir is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gravlax","incorrectAnswers":["Kroppkakor","Smorgasbord","Falukorv"],"question":"What is the name of the Swedish specialty that consists of raw salmon cured in a salt-sugar-dill mixture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scamp","incorrectAnswers":["Sparky","Max","Bolt"],"question":"What is the name of the dog in the movie Lady and the Tramp?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apple Bobbing","incorrectAnswers":["Trick or Treating","Jack o' Lanterns","Wearing Scary Outfits"],"question":"Which Halloween tradition originated from a custom to establish who would get married first?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Amazon","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Danube","The Congo"],"question":"What river has the largest drainage basin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eddy Grant","incorrectAnswers":["Devo","Suzi Quatro","Nick Gilder"],"question":"'Electric Avenue' was a one hit wonder in 1983 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Juarez","incorrectAnswers":["Tijuana","Nogales","Matamoros"],"question":"What is the name of El Paso's twin city on the Mexican side of the border?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Peenemunde","incorrectAnswers":["Hamburg","Lübeck","Rostock"],"question":"Which Baltic seaport was the German rocket centre during WWII?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Deciduous","incorrectAnswers":["Conifer","Gymnosperm","Evergreen"],"question":"From which type of tree do we get hardwood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Writing a diary about her hide from the Germans in WW2","incorrectAnswers":["Winning a nobel prize for her research into radioactivity","Being the first woman to be elected to a head of state position","Being the first woman in space"],"question":"What was Anne Frank famous for?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The War of the Jewels'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Earth","Saturn","Venus"],"question":"The moons Deimos and Phobos orbit which planet in our solar system?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pamela Anderson","incorrectAnswers":["Jennifer Anniston","Kate Moss","Sharon Osborne"],"question":"Who did Tommy Lee of Motley Crue marry in the 90's? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Faroe Islands","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Bangladesh","Italy"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The d in 'door'","incorrectAnswers":["The y in 'yellow'","The r in 'red'","The z in 'zoo'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Black Sabbath","AC/DC","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Which group's first album was entitled 'Piper At the Gates Of Dawn''","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Oregon","Florida","Idaho"],"question":"Which US state is home to the Sequoia National Forest?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Vanuatu is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Antimatter","incorrectAnswers":["Dark matter","Fluid matter","Matter waves"],"question":"What type of matter is a positron?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Ramayana","incorrectAnswers":["The Upanishads","The Bhagavad Gita","The Puranas"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu scripture that contains the story of Sita?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gerald Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Jefferson ","Donald J. Trump","Martin Van Buren "],"question":"Who was the 38th president of the USA, in term during the period 1974–1977?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Detroit","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland","Chicago","Seattle"],"question":"Which city was Axel Foley a cop in before moving to Beverly Hills?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Adam Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Karl Marx","John Maynard Keynes","Milton Friedman"],"question":"\"Wealth of Nations\" was written by which economist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Pullman","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Christopher Tolkien","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Northern Lights'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Halley's Comet","incorrectAnswers":["The Moon","Mars","Venus"],"question":"What was the 1986 Giotto probe designed to study?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"G.I. Joe","incorrectAnswers":["Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles","Scooby Doo","Transformers"],"question":"Which 80's cartoon ended with the phrase: 'And knowing is half the battle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Get off my lawn.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You know how I know that you’re gay?\"","\"Oh, no, it wasn't the airplanes. It was Beauty killed the Beast.\"","\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gran Torino'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Morrisey","incorrectAnswers":["Forissey","Lorissey","Borissey"],"question":"What is the name of the lead singer for the Smiths?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Ireland","Canada"],"question":"In which country is the city of London?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Good King Wenceslas","incorrectAnswers":["Once in Royal David's City","Silent Night","Deck the Halls"],"question":"Which Christmas Carol tells the tale of a 10th century Duke of Bohemia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Scientist who discovered The Theory of Relativity.","incorrectAnswers":["Inventor of the telephone.","38th President of the US.","One of the principal interpreters of Confucianism."],"question":"Which of the following describes Albert Einstein?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Artist","incorrectAnswers":["The Descendants","Extremely Loud & Incredibly Close","The Help"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2011?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Resident Evil","incorrectAnswers":["Left 4 Dead","Dead Space","The Last of Us"],"question":"What horror video game involves surviving environments infested with zombies, and was later adapted into a movie starring Milla Jovovich?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Chestnuts","incorrectAnswers":["Onions","Turkey","Marshmallows"],"question":"According to 'A Christmas Song'', what would you find roasting over an open fire?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Russell Crowe","incorrectAnswers":["Seth Rogen","John Wayne","Ron Perlman"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Gladiator and A Beautiful Mind?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Offspring","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which punk band from the United States released the studio album 'Rise and Fall, Rage and Grace'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"24","incorrectAnswers":["16","20","12"],"question":"How Many Draughts Are On The Board At The Start Of A Game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lebanon","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Israel","Cyprus"],"question":"___________ is the only country in the Middle East that does not have a desert.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Big Bang Theory","incorrectAnswers":["General Relativity","String Theory","Quantum Theory"],"question":"What is the name of the scientific theory that states that the universe began with a singularity?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Agra","incorrectAnswers":["Mumbai","Kolkata","Chennai"],"question":"In Which Indian City Is The Taj Mahal","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kim Basinger","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless","Jacqueline Bisset"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Batman and L.A. Confidential?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Muse","incorrectAnswers":["Tears for Fears","Bullet For My Valentine","Enter Shikari"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'The Resistance'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Hurricane'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Finch","incorrectAnswers":["Jaye Davidson","Malcolm McDowell","Jeff Bridges"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Howard Beale in Network?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dubrovnik","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Geneva","Amsterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Croatia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maseru","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Praia","Bratislava"],"question":"What is the capital city of Lesotho?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The F1 Grand Prix","incorrectAnswers":["The FIFA World Cup","The Africa Cup of Nations","The Hopman Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Motorsports competition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Valkyrie","incorrectAnswers":["Dunkirk","Saving Private Ryan","Schindler's List"],"question":"What is the name of the 2008 WWII film that had the tagline \"Many saw evil. They dared to stop it\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Dominica is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","North Macedonia","Colombia"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Daft Punk","incorrectAnswers":["Gong","Indochine","Nouvelle Vague"],"question":"Which French electronica duo released the song 'One More Time'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rat","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Rabbit","Shrew"],"question":"A __________ can squeeze through an opening no larger than a dime?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"proper names","incorrectAnswers":["prehistoric metaphytes ","prehistoric metazoans ","interactions between organisms and geomorphological processes"],"question":"What is Onomatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Honey ","incorrectAnswers":["Butter","Almond","Lemon"],"question":"From what is mead made?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saturn","incorrectAnswers":["Neptune","Jupiter","Earth"],"question":"Name the second largest planet in the solar system.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Faces","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Deep Purple","Oasis"],"question":"Which band was Rod Stewart a member of before going solo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Guy de Maupassant","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Anatole France","Albert Camus"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Au soleil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a yellow sun having eight broadening rays extending to the edges.","incorrectAnswers":["Two equal horizontal bands of red and white.","Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges.","White with a blue star centered between two equal horizontal blue bands"],"question":"What does the flag of North Macedonia look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Little Mermaid'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of The Gambia is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sarah Jessica Parker","incorrectAnswers":["Audrey Hepburn","Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Sex and the City and Ed Wood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Snooker","Cricket","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Cristiano Ronaldo associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"12","incorrectAnswers":["10","13","11"],"question":"Introduced in 46 BC by Julius Caesar, how many months was the Julian calendar divided into?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thor","incorrectAnswers":["Loki","Odin","Freyja"],"question":"Which Norse god known for his great strength was a protector of peasants and farmers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a yellow star in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","White with a large red disk in the center.","Three equal vertical bands of blue gold and red."],"question":"What does the flag of Vietnam look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mario Puzo","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allan Poe","Stephen King","Dan Brown"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Godfather'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["The Isley Brothers","Van Halen","Devo"],"question":"The song 'Smells Like Teen Spirit' had a well-known cover by Tori Amos, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madagascar","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Myanmar","Latvia"],"question":"Antananarivo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Machu Picchu","incorrectAnswers":["Angkor Wat","Petra","Chichen Itza"],"question":"Which lost city can you see while hiking the Inca trail from Cuzco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gary Oldman","incorrectAnswers":["James Franco","George Clooney","Laurence Fishburne"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Harry Potter and Batman Begins?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia Union","incorrectAnswers":["Philadelphia Indians","Philadelphia Ravens","Philadelphia Reds"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indian Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["Pacific Ocean","Atlantic Ocean","Mediterranean Sea"],"question":"In which body of water is Christmas Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sudan","incorrectAnswers":["Ecuador","Nepal","Malaysia"],"question":"Khartoum is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},